# Joshua Benjamin

256 E. Jackson St. New Holland, PA, 17557

**PHONE**: (717) 538-0866 **E-Mail**: joshuasevendavid@gmail.com

#### **Present Professional Education**

I have completed and received certification from the full-stack (i.e., front-end and back-end technologies) computer coding "bootcamp" through the University of Pennsylvania and Trilogy Educational Services. I graduated on August 8, 2020. Consequently, I plan to pursue a career in this field as a front-end or back-end developer, ideally working for a company that is teamwork/collaboration-oriented. Please see what applicable technologies I've learned below in the Education and Skills and Hobbies sections.

## **Computer Languages and Skills**

HTML, CSS (and various CSS frameworks like Bootstrap, Bulma, Materialize, etc.), JavaScript, jQuery, API client-side server calls (AJAX), HTTP calls, JSON, Node.JS and NPM packages, MySql/Sequelize, Mongo/Mongoose, ReactJS, GIT, Github, CLI

#### **Professional Portfolio and Github Profile**

https://jbenj-upenn.github.io/personal-profile-v2020/ https://github.com/jbenj-upenn

# **Professional Summary**

am an English Language Instructor with expertise in reading, writing, listening, and speaking instruction, with a successful track record of strong student reviews year after year, in addition to positive in-class observations from various colleagues.

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE HIGHLIGHTS**

University of Pennsylvania, English Language Program- Philadelphia, PA
Guest Lecturer – January 2013-present

Drexel University — Philadelphia, PA

Adjunct English Professor- January 2010-present

Millersville University— Millersville, PA

Adjunct English Professor - September 2016-January 2017

Harrisburg Area Community College— Lancaster, PA

English as an Additional Language Instructor- September 2012-June 2013

La Academia Partnership Charter School— Lancaster, PA

ESL Teacher- September 2009-June 2010

Living Word Academy (now Lancaster County Christian School) — Lancaster, PA Spainsh Teacher (High school)- September 2003- January 2008

Instituto Centro America— Quetzaltenango, Guatemala

# **English as a Foreign Language Teacher-** June-July 2005

#### FOCUSES AND SKILLS OF SECONDARY AND HIGHER EDUCATION

Among other things, my experpertise has developed in instruction, student/interpersonal relations, constant professional development, team-building and cooperative activities, organizational development.

#### **EDUCATION**

*University of Pennsylvania/Trilogy Educational Services, (2020)-* received certification as a full-stack computer developer. We have covered HTML; CSS and CSS frameworks (e.g., Bootstrap, Bulma, Materialize); JavaScript; jQuery; Web, Third-Party, and Server-Side APIs; NodeJs and its common packages (e.g., Express, FS); MySQL and Sequelize; Mongo and Mongoose; and ReactJS.

West Chester University, 2010- West Chester, PA; earned a Master's of Arts in TESL (Teaching English as a Second Language); Cumulative GPA- 4.0/4.0

*Millersville University, 2003*- Millersville, PA; earned a double major Bachelor's of Arts in English Linguistics and ESL (English as a Second Language) with a Spanish minor; Cumulative GPA- 3.54/4.0

#### MISCELLANEOUS WORK EXPERIENCE

Stoner Grille, Federal Taphouse, Molly's Pub, Olive Garden, Barny's Restaurant- Bartender Positions

Teen Haven- Youth Counselor

## **SKILLS AND HOBBIES**

## **Systems Expertise**

Microsoft Office, Prezi, Canvas, Blackboard, iWebfolio, Turnitin

#### Languages

Spanish (fluent), some French, and can introduce myself in numerous languages

#### **Hobbies**

Billiards, Poker, "Street" Art/Murals, Reading, Fitness